Currently, we waste about one-third of everything that’s produced,
and that’s globally.
Now, I believe this is going to become
one of the biggest issues.
Right now, when they go to the climate summits,
they aren’t talking about food waste.
But this is where we could really make a big difference.
We waste one-third of everything we produce.
In rich countries, it’s because food is so cheap,
we can throw it away. Right?
Servings are great big. Go to one of these restaurants,
the platter comes out. It’s an amazing amount of food.
You might not eat all of it.
It gets discarded.
In poorer countries, it’s because there’s no infrastructure
to get the crops out of the field. There’s no refrigeration, so the stuff spoils.
So, we produce one-third more than we really need
right now with food waste.
In other words, we grow enough food to feed everybody.
It’s a matter of economics, infrastructure, and distribution.
This is something that’s going to be, I think, a bigger issue moving forward,
and it wouldn’t hurt agriculture to hop on this issue.
When we’re being attacked about the amount of water we use
in California’s dairies, or the amount of methane that we produce,
or the amount of diesel that we burn, maybe we should go right to food waste
and say, “Yes, but consumer, this is on you.”
All we’re doing is producing the food.
It’s not us that’s wasting it.